《訴訟雙雄》前情提要
希拉·阿曼達·塞茲
Sheila Amanda Sazs,
你愿意嫁給我嗎
will you marry me?
我愿意  我愿意嫁給你
Yes, I will marry you.
-我想讓自己合法化  -你不能
- I want to go legit. - You can't.
那我找羅拉·詹森黑進資格考名單
Then I get Lola Jensen to hack into the bar
把我名字加進去  就像她黑哈佛一樣
and just put me in there, just like she did with Harvard.
不想被人抓到辮子
Rule number one of not getting caught,
就是別輕舉妄動
you don't move the goddamn body.
哈維  我無路可走了
Harvey, I'm stuck.
我不能這樣過一輩子
I can't live my whole life like this.
你想讓我幫你建立新公司嗎
You want me to set up your new corporation?
我想讓你加入我的新公司
I want you to join my new corporation.
我們不是律師  我們是投資銀行家
We're not lawyers. We're investment bankers.
我們的工作比你們的厲害多了
Our job blows yours out of the water.
斯科特  我需要你把案子還給路易
Scottie, I need you to give Louis his transaction back.
這和他之前幫你的那個忙有關系嗎
Does this have something to do with that favor he did you?
-是的  -那告訴我是什么事
- Yes. - Tell me what it is.
-不行  -看來我們根本不是
- I can't. - Guess we're not sharing
分享所有秘密了
everything with each other after all.
-斯科特  -你不能二者兼得  哈維
- Scottie. - You can't have it both ways, Harvey.
-路易  我不想要孩子  -你在說什么啊
- Louis, I don't want kids. - What are you talking about?
我不喜歡小孩
I don't like kids.
我為了你愿意放棄哈佛
I was willing to give up Harvard for you.
你就不能為我放棄點什么嗎
You can't give up something for me?
我知道  我能說兩句嗎
I understand. Can I just say something please?
我知道你一直說我不會永遠這樣
I know you keep saying that I won't feel this way forever,
但為什么送咖喱雞的人
but why is it when the guys shows up
遲到了四十分鐘
with chicken vindaloo 40 minutes late
還沒拿烤餅和銀制餐具
with no naan and no silverware,
我不僅沒有甩他一臉酸辣醬
instead of throwing the chutney in his face,
還謝了他  又給他二十塊錢小費
I'm thanking him and I am tipping him $20?
你要告訴我這到底是怎么回事嗎
Do you want to tell me why that happens?
我不管  我厭惡自己
I don't care. I hate myself.
我厭惡我的人生
I hate my life.
我愛的女人離開了  我的心支離破碎
The woman I love is gone, my heart is broken,
我真的  老實跟你說吧
and I really-- to be honest with you,
我不想活了
I just don't have the will to live.
別掛電話  是我手下的初級律師
Hold on. It's my associate.
卡特里娜
Katrina.
路易  現在是7點55分
Louis, it's 7:55.
我八點有個會
Yeah. I have an 8:00 a.m.
幫我兜一下  事實上  所有事都幫我搞定
Please cover it for me. In fact, cover everything,
除非律所著火了  而且希拉在里面
and unless the building is on fire and Sheila's in it,
-不然我都不去了  -路易  怎么回事
- I'm not coming in. - Louis, what happened?
你想知道怎么回事  那我就告訴你
You wanna know what happened? I'll tell you what happened.
我的心碎成渣渣了
My heart's been shattered into a thousand million pieces,
如果我沒法把心思放在工作上
and if I can't put my heart into my work,
那我就干脆不去工作了  所以...
then I'm not gonna do any work at all, so...
那你什么時候回來
How long do you think you'll be out?
不知道  也許今天  也許明天
I don't know. Today, tomorrow,
也許今年都不會回去了
the rest of the year.
別再打給我了
You know, just don't call here again
因為我不會再接這個號碼了
because I'm not gonna answer the number.
醫生
Doc?
利普希茨醫生
Dr. Lipschitz?
喂
Hello?
你他媽坑我呢  根本沒到五十分鐘
What, are you shitting me? That was not 50 minutes.
在外面等我  夠厚顏無恥的
Waiting outside for me? Bold gesture.
打了三個電話都沒接  總得做點什么吧
I called you three times. I had to do something.
-你心里一定很不舒服吧  -是的
- You must be feeling bad. - I am.
何必呢  你只是做好本份工作而已
What for? You're just doing your job.
斯科特  對不起
Scottie, I'm sorry.
路易那件事  我也不想這么做的
What happened with Louis, I didn't like doing it.
-但你還是做了  -我現在想請你
- Yeah, but you still did it. - And what I'm doing now
讓這事過去
is asking you to let it go.
哈維  我生氣不是因為你選擇路易而不是我
Harvey, it's not that you picked Louis over me.
而是你不肯告訴我原因
It's that you wouldn't tell me why.
我是不能告訴你  有區別的
I couldn't tell you why. There's a difference.
請你相信我
And I'm asking you to trust me.
好吧
Okay.
我可以不計較  但你也不能
I can let it go, but keeping things from me
什么事都瞞著我  行嗎
just can't keep happening, okay?
我說不好到底行不行
I can't tell you whether or not that's okay,
但我一定不能告訴你原因
and I definitely can't tell you why.
太早說笑了嗎
Too soon?
你要怎么補償我
What are you going to do to make it up to me?
現在不行
Nothing right now.
我要帶邁克去馬拉松跑鞋公司早午餐
I'm taking Mike to the Marathon Footwear brunch.
你要攜伴參加首次公開募股會
You're taking a date to an I.P.O. event?
-真貼心  -他不是我的伴侶
- That's so cute. - It's not a date.
他可不會向我獻身
He's never gonna put out.
你不帶我去真是可惜了
Well, it's too bad that you're not taking me
因為我可是準備讓你...
because I was thinking of letting you...
斯佩克特先生
Mr. Specter.
我是詹姆斯·柯靈
James Quelling.
我有點趕時間  柯靈先生
I'm in a bit of a hurry, Mr. Quelling.
-我想幫你一個忙  -我不需要人幫忙
- I want to do you a favor. - I don't need any favors.
你需要的  除非你想看到周五的頭條寫著
Yeah, you do, unless you want Friday's headline to read,
"馬拉松跑鞋公司建造害死孩子的游樂場"
"Marathon Footwear builds playgrounds that kill children."
我客戶建造的是幫助孩子的游樂場
My client builds playgrounds that help children.
所用的合成物卻充滿毒質
And uses a synthetic full of toxins to do it.
我不知道你是誰
Look, I don't know who you are,
但我知道你想干什么  沒用的
but I know what you're trying to do, and it isn't gonna work.
我是個講理之人
Look, I'm a reasonable man.
現在對你委托人來說是個重要時刻
This is a huge moment for your client.
我會拖到周五才公開
I won't file this before Friday.
你認為我會坐視不管你敲詐我的委托人嗎
You think I'm gonna let you extort my client?
不  我認為你會保護你的委托人
No, I think you're gonna protect your client
不讓一件索賠案毀了他們
from a claim that could ruin them.
事實上  我就指望你這么做呢
In fact, I'm counting on it.
辦公室挺漂亮  好好享受早午餐吧
Nice offices. Enjoy that brunch.
-我收到了一份工作邀約  -天哪  誰給的
- I got a job offer. - Holy shit. From who?
昨晚  喬納森·西德威爾
Last night. Jonathan Sidwell.
他的律師不是路易嗎
But I thought Louis was his lawyer.
他不要我做他的律師
He doesn't want me to be his lawyer.
他要我入伙
He wants me to be a partner.
-投資銀行  -對
- Investment banking? - Yeah.
-然后呢  -我不知道
- And? - I don't know.
-你怎么想  -我不知道
- What do you think? - I don't know.
-你怎么看  -我愛你
- What do you think? - I think that I love you,
你想做的就是我想做的
and what you want to do is what I want you to do.
我不知道該怎么辦
I don't know what to do.
好吧  你跟哈維說了嗎
Okay. Did you talk to Harvey?
如果我跟他說  他只會曲解為
If I do that, all he'll hear is, "Hey, Harvey,
"哈維  謝謝你為我做的一切
"Thanks for doing everything for me.
我準備辭職了"
I'm thinking about quitting."
但你說你沒把他看作是上司
No, but you said that you don't think of him as just your boss.
你當他是朋友
You consider him a friend.
-那又怎樣  -那如果他不能為你著想
- So? - So if he can't have an honest conversation
跟你好好談談
with your best interests in mind,
那他就不是你的朋友  也不該做你的上司
he's not your friend, and-- and he shouldn't be your boss.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：愛卿遛小鳥   草草   某豚   王大可   七個柚子醬
翻譯：又是王大可   月月     校對：油炸電風扇   月月
時間軸：aaaaaaaaaaBao   憑陵新月   雯雯記
后期：冰冰愛尖尖       總監：swears
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
訴 訟 雙 雄
第三季   第十五集
我有事要跟你說
I have to talk to you about something.
除非你的事價值超過5.75億美元
Well, unless its value is in excess of $575 million,
不然就得等著了
it can wait.
好  我的事能等
Yeah. Yeah, it can wait.
很好  除非我們能處理好這件事
Good because our I.P.O. is in jeopardy
不然首次公開募股可就岌岌可危了
unless we can deal with this.
危害兒童  這些游樂場才剛開放
Endangering children? Wait, these things just opened.
這索賠就是扯淡
This is a bullshit claim.
也許  但在正確日子的扯淡索賠
Maybe, but a bullshit claim on the right day
也比鬼日子的完美索賠攻擊力更大
is better than a great claim on a bullshit day.
這話是你自己想到的嗎
Did you come up with that all by yourself?
我祖母教我的
My grandmother taught it to me.
-需要我做什么  -我要你挖出
- What do you need me to do? - I need you to find
這個叫柯靈的家伙的所有事
everything there is to know about this Quelling guy.
哈維  為什么不干脆給他錢就算了
Harvey, why don't you just pay him off?
保護首次公開募股
Protect the I.P.O.?
我為這一天勞心勞力
I worked my ass off for this day.
他想敲詐我  我可不會被什么
He's trying to hijack it. I'm not gonna be extorted
毫無名氣的狗屎敲詐
by some piece of shit I've never heard of.
好吧  這就去辦
Okay. On it.
杰西卡
Jessica.
唐娜  有什么事嗎
Donna, what can I do for you?
我剛剛走過前臺
I was just walking by reception,
我覺得你可能會想知道
and I thought you might like to know--you know,
-因為這是你的公司  -唐娜  直說
- because it's your firm and- - Donna, get to it.
查爾斯·范·戴克在大堂
Charles Van Dyke is in the lobby.
-現在嗎  -三十秒之前
- Right now? - 30 seconds ago.
你來找我是對的
You were right to come to me.
要我去把他打發走嗎
Would you like me to send him on his way?
我更想自己去對付查爾斯·范·戴克
I prefer to take care of Charles Van Dyke myself.
很好
Excellent.
你再怎么盯著它  查爾斯
You can stare at it all you want, Charles,
也無法改變什么
but it's not going to change.
我只是在想
I was just thinking,
真不敢相信你把郵件室小工的名字
"I can't believe you put the mailroom boy's name
-掛在墻上了  -我想你真正的意思是
- on the wall." - I think what you mean is
你仍不敢相信你的名字居然也會被摘下來
that you can't believe yours was ever taken off.
那事我早放下了
I put that behind me years ago.
你來干什么  查爾斯
What are you doing here, Charles?
我們去你辦公室談吧
I suggest we go in your office and talk.
在這兒就挺好
Right here is just fine.
你想怎么樣
What do you want?
我要我的股利分紅上調30%
I want a 30% increase in my dividend check.
-滾蛋吧  -我就猜到你會這么說
- Good-bye, Charles. - I thought you'd say that.
這是我要求審計你們賬簿的正式通知書
This is formal notice of my demand to audit your books.
周五前回復
You have until Friday to comply.
我們把你趕出去的時候你就放棄這個權利了
You gave up this right when we ran you out of town.
但你忘記我保留了
I think you're forgetting I retain that right
在股息發生實質改變的情況下進行審計的權利
in the event of any material change in my dividend.
你的股息提高了
Your dividend went up.
這就是實質改變啊
Materially.
你覺得我們在隱瞞盈利
You think we're hiding profits.
據我對你的了解  你總有所隱瞞
From what I know of you, you're always hiding something.
-我就快點說了  吉姆  -是詹姆斯
- I'm gonna make it fast, Jim. - James.
你前妻可不是那么喊你的
That's not what your ex-wife calls you.
她喊你吉姆
She calls you Jim.
那還算是比較好的稱呼了
That's one of the nicer names she uses.
她現在喊你的花樣可多了
She's been calling you a lot these days.
你們知道我離婚了
Wow, you found out I'm divorced.
好吧  那我撤訴了
Well, I'll withdraw the lawsuit.
不是離婚的問題  吉姆
It's not the divorce, Jimbo,
而是你故意輸掉煙草危害訴訟后
it's the huge wall of mounting debt that's closing in on you
欠下的一屁股債
since you tanked the tobacco litigation.
我不是故意的  就是輸了
I didn't tank it. I lost.
你不止是輸了
You didn't just lose.
你本來有一份十分豐厚的和解交易
You had an offer that would have set you up for life.
但你卻賭了一把  尋求判決
Instead, you rolled the dice, went to verdict,
結果滿盤皆輸
and now you got nothing.
所以你妻子才離開你
Which is why your wife left you,
現在你又拿個虛構的索賠來找我們麻煩
and now you're coming after us with a fabricated claim.
我沒有虛構什么  我有專家的報告
I didn't fabricate anything. I have expert reports here.
那不過是一份操場制造材料
You've got one report of possible toxins
可能有毒性的報告
in the playground material.
而且沒有任何孩子生病
And not one sick child.
而你們周五有首次募股
And you have an I.P.O. on Friday,
如果那天早上這份訴訟出現在報刊上
and if this suit appears in the Journal that morning,
你覺得募股開始后
what do you think the stock price is gonna be
股價走勢會如何
when they ring that bell?
被你將住了  報價吧
Got me. Give me your number.
-十萬  了事  -了事
- 100,000 and we're done. - Done.
-我們會起草文件  -我弄好了
- We'll draw up the paperwork. - I've got it right here.
但有一點  今后
But one thing, this precludes you
你不得再代表其他原告提出同一指控
from representing any other plaintiffs with the same action.
被你將住了
You got me.
我還有一百個原告在等著呢
I have 100 other plaintiffs waiting in the wings.
你們剛剛避免了一千萬的損失
That's a $10 million hit you just avoided.
這樣吧
I tell you what.
給我一百萬  我們就真了事
Give me a million, and we're really done.
詹姆斯  這筆錢償還你的債務綽綽有余了
James, this covers your debts and gets you out from under.
所以你覺得我會被小錢打發嗎
You think that means I'm gonna take less than it's worth?
-這根本不值錢  -今天值錢
- It isn't worth anything. - It is today.
你們知道怎么找我
You know where to reach me.
你不是說你最高能接受
Thought you said you were willing to go
-五十萬嗎  -那是之前
- as high as 500,000. - Yeah, that was before
我當時還不知道對手是什么人
I realized what we were dealing with.
他欠錢不是因為離婚
This guy doesn't owe money 'cause he got divorced.
而是因為欠錢才會離婚
He got divorced 'cause he owes money.
-什么意思  -他是個賭徒
- What are you talking about? - He's a gambler.
這有什么用
How does that help us?
他不知道我也是
He doesn't know I'm one.
路易呢
Where's Louis?
-杰西卡  -他人呢
- Jessica. - Where is he?
他不接電話  也不回郵件
He's not answering his phone. He's not answering his emails.
問題是  我不知道他...
The thing is I don't know if he--
卡特里娜  你守大門的那套
Katrina, your job as gatekeeper
在我這兒不適用  我再問你一次
does not apply to me, so I'm going to ask you one more time.
路易為什么不在樓里
Why isn't Louis in the building?
他肯定還在法院
He must still be in court.
-我能做什么嗎  -你能做的
- Is there something I can do? - What you can do
就是找到路易  讓他想辦法
is find Louis and have him come up with a way around
避免我們被查賬
this demand to look at our books.
我跟他說什么時候需要
When should I tell him you need it?
昨天
Yesterday.
你說得對  柯靈有賭局
You were right. Quelling's got a game.
-哪晚  -每晚
- What night? - Every night.
你最好知道今晚的賭局在哪
Well, I hope you know where tonight's game is because--
很好
Great.
我們去
You and I are going.
什么
What?
我得到了一份工作邀請  哈維
I got a job offer, Harvey.
今晚約好去邊喝邊談的
Supposed to go have drinks to talk about it tonight.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
我可以改期  但是...
I can move it, it's just, that's...
這是我遲疑的原因
that's why I hesitated.
-什么時候  -你指什么
- When? - When what?
你什么時候收到的邀請
When'd you get the job offer?
-前兩天晚上  -你沒跟我說
- The other night. - And you didn't mention it.
我當時不知道該怎么想
I didn't know what I thought.
-現在想清楚了  -不是
- And now you do? - No. It's--
是誰
Who?
喬納森·西德威爾
Jonathan Sidwell.
分拆的主意
The spin-off idea?
-嗯  -我該料到的
- Yeah. - I should have known.
他要你做他的法律總顧問嗎
He wants you to be his general counsel?
不  他想讓我做投資銀行家
No, he wants to make me an investment banker.
如果是我  我就接受
Well, if it were me... I'd take it.
什么  為什么
What? Why?
因為你在那兒也會像在這兒一樣游刃有余
Because you can compete there like you do here
而且還不用擔心東窗事發
with nothing hanging over your head.
如果我不想離開律師界呢
What if I don't want to stop being a lawyer?
那就別接受
Well, then don't take the job.
你想我說什么啊
I mean, what do you want from me?
-我想要你的建議  -我剛剛說了
- I want your advice. - I just gave you my advice.
你只是說你會怎么做
No, you told me what you would do.
我想知道你覺得我該怎么做
I want to know what you think I should do.
邁克  上周你還說你愿不惜一切
Mike, last week, you said you'd do anything
不再做個騙子  所以我建議你接受
to stop being a fraud, so my advice is take it.
還是大聯盟  只是不同的賽事
Still be in the majors, just be a different sport.
打擾  你有空嗎
Excuse me, do you have a minute?
我們兩人向來不...
Look, you and I have never--
沒錯  的確
No, we haven't.
我需要你幫助
I need your help.
你來找我的話
You must be scraping the bottom of the barrel
-一定是走投無路了  -是關于路易
- if you're coming to me. - It's about Louis.
-他和希拉沒戲了  -太糟了
- He and Sheila are done. - That's awful.
比那還糟
It's worse than awful.
杰西卡需要他現在負責一樁案子
Jessica needs him on a case right now.
而他不肯出門  甚至不接電話
He won't leave his apartment. He won't even answer his phone.
那我現在過去一趟
Then I'll just go over there right now.
沒用的
That won't work.
即使好使了  也來不及
Even if it did, we don't have time.
那你來干什么
So then why are you here?
瑞秋  你不信任我
Rachel, you don't trust me.
這我懂  但路易讓我替他應付好
I get that, but Louis asked me to cover for him,
所以我就要這么做
and that is what I'm going to do.
你是這兒最棒的律師助理
You're the best paralegal here,
也是他的朋友
and you're his friend.
-幫不幫忙  -幫
- So will you help me or not? - I will.
我知道你今晚能做什么來彌補我了
So...I figured out what you can do to make it up to me tonight.
我以為我們之間沒事了
I thought we were good.
對  只是  我覺得還有些余怒未消
Yeah, I'm just--I'm feeling some residual anger.
斯科特  我現在有點忙
Scottie, I'm kind of busy right now,
而且晚上有事情
and I have plans tonight.
帶邁克去另一場公開募股約會嗎
Taking Mike on another I.P.O. date?
-有什么區別  -聽起來夠神秘
- What difference does it make? - Sounds mysterious.
我打賭你不能說是什么事
Bet you can't tell me what it is.
-我要去玩牌  -玩牌嗎
- I'm playing poker. - Poker?
-我能來嗎  -工作上的事
- Can I come? - It's a work thing.
你帶邁克去干工作上的事
You bring Mike to work things.
斯科特  告訴過你我很忙  你不能來
Scottie, I told you I'm busy. You can't come.
我能繼續工作了嗎
Can I get back to work now?
-你吃錯什么藥了  -沒有
- What got into you? - Nothing.
只是有時候當我在辦公室  我是在辦公
Sometimes at the office, I'm working.
算你有理  老板
Fair enough, boss.
你確定要這么玩嗎
Are you sure that's how you want to play that?
玩什么  我很忙的事實嗎
Play what, the fact that I'm busy?
這么個事實  你對著她發作
The fact that you just snapped at her
但我們都知道  你到底為什么發火
when we both know what you're really angry about.
我沒發火  我只是很煩被打斷
I'm not angry. I'm annoyed at the interruption.
你發火  因為邁克想離開
You're angry that Mike wants to leave,
你卻遷怒在她身上
and you just took it out on her.
-我沒為那件事發火  -對  但你受傷了
- I'm not angry about that. - No, you're hurt,
用憤怒掩飾傷心  但我知道你自己并不清楚
and the anger covers the hurt, but I knew you didn't know that.
我只是很煩被打斷
I was annoyed about the interruption
-我現在也很煩  一個道理  -胡說
- just like I'm annoyed right now. - Bullshit.
我跟你感同身受
You're feeling exactly what I'm feeling.
邁克離開的消息是讓人不好受
The idea of Mike leaving sucks,
你越早繞開這個情緒
and the sooner you get your brain around that,
就能越早采取措施
the sooner you can maybe do something about it.
我能繼續工作了嗎
Can I get back to work now?
隨時都可以
You can get back to work whenever you want.
但如果你只想埋著頭逃避問題
But if all you're gonna do is stick your head in the sand,
那可就連打斷你工作的
then you're not going to have
初級律師或者女朋友都沒有了
an associate or a girlfriend to get back to work from.
-你給她了嗎  -給她了
- You give it to her? - I gave it to her.
她有什么懷疑嗎
She suspect anything?
如果她懷疑了  我就不會站在這兒了
I wouldn't be standing here if she did.
-然后  -她覺得非常棒
- And? - She thought it was awesome.
那是當然
Well, she should.
路易不僅想出來了個好辦法
Louis didn't just come up with a way
保證查爾斯·范·戴克查不了我們的賬
to keep Charles Van Dyke out of our books.
還把他整得一敗涂地
Louis came up with a way to blow him out of the water.
那個路易  真是個厲害的律師
That Louis. He is one hell of an attorney.
-謝謝你  路易  -稍后見  路易
- Thank you, Louis. - Right back at you, Louis.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
-別太習慣了  -別擔心
- Don't get used to it. - Don't worry.
我沒打算重新在這兒工作
I'm not looking to work here again.
雖然不在這兒  但你是在找工作
Not here, but you are looking to work?
我總能一眼看穿你的鬼話的  查爾斯
I've always been able to see through your bullshit, Charles.
所以我才給你提供這些
Which is why I'm offering you these,
一共五個案子
five cases.
我們合伙  利潤對半分
We're co-counsel, split the profits 50/50.
可以向全世界宣布  你重出江湖
It announces to the world that you are back in business,
這才是你真正想要的
which is what you really want.
你帶著禮物來找我
You came to me bearing gifts.
我還留著當初的卡片
I still have the card.
"致我的雇主  感謝你所做的一切"
"To the man who hired me for all you've done."
兩天后  你把我撇到了一邊
Two days later, you shoved me out.
我就當你不打算接受我的提議
I take this to mean you're passing on my offer.
我這是把你的提議踩在腳下
I'm shiting on your offer.
好吧查爾斯  你說的沒錯
Okay, Charles. You were right.
你的股利分紅確實數額不對
Your dividend check did have the wrong amount,
但從今往后  數額就會變正確了
But from now on, it's going to have the right amount,
那就是零
zero.
我可不這么認為
I don't think so.
你手握退出協定的律所  已經不復存在了
oh, the firm you had your exit agreement with no longer exists.
我們變成了皮爾遜-達比
We became Pearson Darby,
后來是皮爾遜-斯佩克特
then Pearson Specter,
你一點資格都沒有
which means you're not entitled to a thing.
我們的協議精神可不是這么說的
That's not in the spirit of our agreement.
你的聲明也沒這么說
And neither is your claim.
只有一個問題
There's only one problem.
你看附屬細則的時候真該更仔細點
You should have dug deeper into the fine print.
根據你的細則
The entity referred to in our agreement
我們協議中提到的內容可解釋為
is defined in your bylaws as
"任何以杰西卡·皮爾遜
"Any partnership in which
為冠名的合伙人關系"
the name partner is Jessica Pearson."
你居然不知道
You didn't know.
我的數字剛剛乘以三了
My number just tripled.
由你決定
Your call.
我們的聽證會在禮拜五
Our hearing is friday.
你們在玩牌嗎
You guys playing cards?
你別自不量力  這是給真正的玩家玩的
You're out of your league. This game is for real players.
不試試怎么知道
Why don't I give it a try?
門檻費兩萬五
Buy-in is 25,000.
-上限是什么  -沒有上限
- What's the limit? - There is no limit.
大概我是在自不量力
Maybe I am out of my league.
加注四萬五
Raise $45,000.
你可得全押了
I'm putting you all-in.
我見過你這樣的
I've seen guys like you before.
你以為大賭注可以壓得住我
You think if you bully me with your big stack,
我會臨陣畏縮
I'm gonna run and hide.
這就是我和你的不同了  吉姆
Here's the difference between you and me, Jimbo,
我輸了  就再出兩萬五
I lose, I pull out another 25 grand,
然后再出兩萬五
and another 25 after that.
你輸了  就一無所有了
You lose, you've got nothing.
你在虛張聲勢
You're bluffing.
要么跟注  要么起身走人
Then call or get up and walk away,
但我和你面對面太多次了
But I've sat across from you 1,000 times before.
你不會走的
You won't walk.
艱難獲勝
Tough beat.
拿走你的戰利品吧
Take your winnings.
什么戰利品
What winnings?
我覺得也許我倆能來點討價還價
I thought maybe it was time we do a little negotiating.
-你知道我的出價了  -我有加價
- Well, you have my offer. - I have a counter.
-洗耳恭聽  -我希望基本工資提高50%
- I'm all ears. - I want a 50% increase in base salary.
保證分紅不與投資收益掛鉤
I want a guaranteed bonus not tied to our investment returns,
四周年假  我還要入股
A four-week vacation, and I want a piece.
-入股嗎  -對
- A piece? - A piece.
-不行  -不能入股嗎
- No. - No piece?
不能討價還價  我知道在想什么
No negotiating. Look, I know what you're doing.
你下不了決心
You can't make up your mind,
所以希望我來替你做決定
So you want me to make it up for you.
但我不希望人們為了錢而跟著我
But I don't want someone who's with me for the money.
我希望跟著我的人
I want someone who's with me
是因為想變得厲害才入這行
'cause they want to kick some ass.
我確實挺厲害
I do kick ass.
如果你現在就接受這份工作
And if you want to take this job right now,
我就認認真真跟你商討
I will negotiate in good faith.
但你不想
But you don't.
現在還不想
I don't yet.
明天起
Starting tomorrow,
我會開始面試其他人
I'll be interviewing other people.
一旦我找到合適的人選
Once I find the right person,
這工作就沒了
job is gone.
我不會在你們上市的兩天前撤訴的
I'm not dropping my suit when you're going public in two days.
詹姆斯  你肯定讀過海辛頓石油的相關報道
James, you've read all about Hessington Oil.
當時的情形完全不利于我
The odds were stacked against me.
我還是贏了  因為我生來就是贏家
I won anyway, because I win.
你贏了  是因為愛德華·達比出了頭
You won because Edward Darby came forward.
你碰運氣而已
You got lucky.
像你這樣的人  總是覺得別人是碰運氣
Guys like you always think other people get lucky.
我不碰運氣
I don't get lucky.
我創造自己的運氣
I make my own luck,
這個案子  你會一敗涂地
And in this case, it's bleeding you dry.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
就在剛剛
Right there.
你泄了底  你沒錢了
You just gave me your tell. You have no other money.
你玩完了  那堆牌注里有十萬美元
You're done. There's $100,000 in that pile.
正好是我們給你提的價
It's the exact amount of the deal we offered you.
簽了它
Sign it.
我們明天再完成文件
We'll fix the paperwork tomorrow.
這是一千美金  幫我兌現
This is $1,000. Cash me out.
他今晚不再玩了
He doesn't play anymore the rest of the night.
你沒睡好
You didn't sleep well.
我根本沒睡
I didn't sleep at all.
這確實是個重大決定
It's a big decision.
你到現在也沒說過你的想法
You still haven't told me what you think.
邁克  我不能幫你做決定
Mike, I can't make the decision for you.
我沒想讓你幫我做決定
I don't want you to make it for me.
我只想知道你的看法
I just want to know what you think.
我已經跟你說過我會
And I already told you that I will support you
-支持你的所有決定  -你表示支持的
- with whatever you decide.  - And the way you can support me
方法就是告訴我你的看法
right now is by telling me how you feel.
-這不應該由我說  -不應該由你說
- It's not my place. - Not your place?
承認吧  你想讓我接受那份工作
Just admit it. You want me to take the job,
但你不敢說
but you're too afraid to say it.
好吧  你想聽實話嗎
Okay, you want to know the truth?
你早就知道自己想怎么做了
You already know what you want to do.
如果我還試圖改變你的想法并且以后出了錯
And if I try to change your mind and it goes wrong,
我很害怕你會在這事上做文章
then I'm afraid you're gonna hold it against me.
你就說吧
Would you just say it?
是的  我希望你接受那份工作
Yes. I want you to take the job.
我知道你很熱愛現在的工作
Look, I know that you love what you do,
但你每天都要帶著被抓的可能性
but every day, you go into work with the possibility
去上班  這件事在一點點的吞噬著你
of being caught, and it is eating away at you.
如果你留在這  這個情況永遠不會改變
If you stay there, that's just not gonna change.
-杰西卡  事情進展  -如何
- Jessica. How did-- - It go?
我來告訴你進展如何  我被害慘了
I'll tell you how it went. I got hung out to dry.
什么  不可能  那辦法很高明
What? No, it was a good move.
如果不是我們自己的章程
Oh, it would have been
推翻了這個辦法的話  那確實高明
if our own bylaws didn't supersede it.
那不可能
Th-that's impossible.
關鍵信息被隱藏在復雜難懂的小字注釋中了
It was convoluted and buried in the fine print,
如果是路易·利特的話一定會想到
and something Louis Litt never would have missed.
看著我的眼睛說我說錯了嗎
Look me in the eye and tell me I'm wrong.
你說的沒錯  他一定能想到
You're not. He wouldn't have missed it.
所以當你走進我的辦公室
So when you came into my office
告訴我路易想出了這個辦法的時候
and told me Louis had come up with that move,
你就是在蒙我
you were full of shit.
對不起  我只是想幫忙
I'm sorry. I wanted to help.
這種事只會發生這一次
Well, that kind of thing only happens once.
你知道我為什么這么說嗎
You know how I know it's not gonna happen again?
收拾好你的東西
Pack up your shit.
我不在乎你和哈維有什么協議
I don't care what kind of deal you have with Harvey.
你可以走了
You're done.
你為什么不告訴她
Why wouldn't you tell her?
我說了我會幫他打掩護
I said I would cover.
我沒說只有在情況允許的條件下才幫他
I didn't say I would cover when it suited me.
是的  但他也不想你因為這件事被開除啊
Yeah, but he wouldn't want you to get fired over this.
我應該被開除  我讓杰西卡出丑
I should be fired. I let Jessica look stupid.
卡特里娜
Katrina--
謝謝你幫我  瑞秋
Thank you for your help, Rachel.
我很感激
I really appreciate it,
但如果你不介意的話  我想一個人呆著
but if you don't mind, I'd like to be alone.
他不在
He's not here.
去哪兒了
Where is he?
說實話  我不知道
To tell you the truth, I don't know.
他只說他昨晚睡得很晚
All he said was he had a late night.
好吧  我等下再來
Well, I can come back.
-我只是  -你準備接受那份工作了
- I was just--  - You're taking the job,
是不是
Aren't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道
Yeah, you do.
你只是不想承認而已
You just don't want to admit it.
是的  我準備接受那份工作了
Yeah. I'm taking the job.
該死的
God damn it.
你知道那個人都為你做了些什么嗎
Do you know what that man has done for you?
你知道他費了多少力才開始信任別人嗎
Do you know what it took for him to start trusting someone?
-唐娜  -別打斷我
- Donna-- - Don't interrupt me.
有個人在你面前甩下些錢
So someone's dangling some money in front of you.
-跟錢沒關系  -我不在乎跟什么有關
- It's not about that. - I don't care what it's about.
我要把他不愿說的話告訴你
I'm gonna say what he won't.
他需要你
He needs you.
你需要這份工作  如果你不明白這點
You need this job, and if you can't see that,
也許你確實應該離開
then you might as well just leave right now.
唐娜  有人為我找到了一條出路
Donna, someone's offering me a way out.
-那你不在乎他嗎  -我當然在乎
- So you don't care about him. - Of course I do,
但我也在乎和瑞秋一起的生活
but I also care about my life with Rachel.
我不想在過這樣的生活了
I don't want to live my life like this anymore.
那你最好成為這個城市里
Then you better be the best goddamn investment banker
最好的投資銀行家
this city has ever seen.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
斯科特  很抱歉我對你發脾氣了
Scottie, I'm sorry I was angry in your direction,
但我發火是因為別的事情
but it was really about something else.
我猜猜  唐娜把你的感受告訴你了
Let me guess, Donna explained your feelings to you,
現在你來跟我道歉了
and now you're here to apologize.
也許吧
Maybe.
別的事情到底是什么事
What was the something else?
有人給了邁克一個工作機會
Mike got a job offer.
但你不想讓他走
And you don't want him to do it.
我不想
No, I don't.
如果你想讓他留下來
well, if you want him to stay,
你知道該怎樣做嗎
you know what's actually a nice tactic?
告訴他你想讓他留下來
Telling him you want him to stay.
什么
What?
我不知道"告訴我你到底發生了什么事"
Had I known "Tell me what's going on with you"
原來等于"我會告訴你應該怎么做"
meant "I'm going to tell you what to do,"
知道的話我就不來找你了
I might not have taken you up on it.
好吧
Oh, okay. Mmm.
-你先進去吧  -好吧
- I'll see you in there. - Okay.
文件帶來了嗎
You have that paperwork for me?
我確實有東西給你  但不是你要的文件
Well, I got something for you, but it's not that.
經過昨晚你還沒有長記性嗎
Didn't you learn your lesson last night?
我學會了傾聽
I learned to listen.
你說話的時候
When you talked,
提到了海辛頓石油  我就去查了一下
you mentioned Hessington Oil, so I looked back into it.
結果發現你并不是自己制造運氣
Turns out you don't create your own luck.
是你的手下替你制造的
Your associate does.
你這么說是什么意思
What the hell are you talking about?
他與哈羅德·甘德森合謀
He conspired with Harold Gunderson
對你們自己的客戶發起了訴訟
to file a lawsuit against your own client
好讓你去賄賂證人不出庭作證
so you could bribe witnesses not to testify.
我們沒有賄賂任何人
We didn't bribe anyone.
-那是合法的訴訟和解  -別跟我說
- That was a legal settlement. - Don't try to tell me
兩個一起上法學院  畢業后一同工作的
two rookie associates who went to law school together
新手律師沒有共謀
and started at the same firm made this happen
-促成了此事  -我不用告訴你任何事
- without collusion. - I don't need to tell you
因為根本沒什么好說的
anything 'cause there's nothing to tell.
你肯定和什么人說了些什么
Well, you're gonna have to tell someone something,
因為那案子頭一天發起  第二天就和解
because that suit was filed one day, settled the next,
那些證人也取消了去紐約的機票
and those witnesses cancelled their flights to New York.
那就是賄賂
That is a bribe,
當我把這件事告訴律師協會后
And when I bring it to the attention of the bar,
你和你的手下就慘了
you and your associate are going to be in deep shit.
現在看看是誰泄底了
Now who showed his tell?
你的錢還給你
Here's your money back.
我去律師協會告發你  或者兩百萬和解
And either I go to the bar, or you settle for $2 million.
明天之前答復我
You have until tomorrow.
-邁克在哪  -在里面
- Where is Mike? - He's in there.
哈維
Harvey--
-哈維  -等一下
- Harvey. - Not now.
-打電話給羅拉·詹森  -什么
- You need to call Lola Jensen. - What?
你要讓她黑進律師協會
You need to get her to hack into the bar
然后把你的名字加進去
and put your name in.
你在說什么
What the hell are you talking about?
一周前  你告訴我首要的原則是
A week ago, you told me that the number one rule
不要有任何行動
was not to move the goddamn body.
一周前  沒有人在打探你
A week ago, people weren't sniffing around you.
-哈維  那份工作  -這與那份工作無關
- Harvey, my job offer is not-- - This isn't about your offer.
柯靈知道了你與哈羅德·甘德森
Quelling knows about your bullshit lawsuit
那個狗屁官司了
with Harold Gunderson.
他去檢舉我了
He turned me in?
沒有  但如果我們不屈服他會的
No, but he will if we don't cave.
-他什么都證明不了  -他不用證明
- He can't prove anything. - He doesn't have to.
他把你交給律師協會
He hands you in to the bar,
他們查一下你的名字  我們就完了
they look you up, we're done.
我離開這里就沒事了
Not if I'm not here.
你來就是為了說這事
Oh, that's why you're in here.
-你打算接受那份工作  -是
- You're taking the job. - I am.
你以為只要你不在這里工作
And you think an addicted gambler
那個失去了老婆孩子和房子的賭棍
who lost his wife, his child, and his house is gonna stop
就會不再糾纏你了嗎
coming for you just because you're not working here?
你自己也說過  黑進資格考名單
You said it yourself. Hacking into the bar
比我現在犯的罪還重一倍
is twice the crime I've been committing.
我告訴你  柯靈正在受審
I am telling you Quelling is on the trail.
如果你不這么做  我們就會被抓住
You don't do this, we're gonna get caught.
-一定有其它辦法的  -沒有
- There's got to be another way. - There isn't.
-我不信  -那你最好
- I don't believe that. - Then you better
趕緊想個主意出來  不然明早
figure something out fast, because tomorrow morning,
我們就完了  就算你辭職也無濟于事
we're done, and you quitting isn't gonna change that.
立刻來見我  J
你不能解雇卡特里娜·班尼特
You can't fire Katrina Bennett.
我可以解雇任何想解雇的人
I can fire whoever I want to.
她是在為路易掩飾
She was covering for Louis.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
路易的訂婚無疾而終了  他很消沉
Louis's engagement is over, and he's losing it.
他不來工作  不接電話
He won't come in to work, he won't pick up his phone,
而且不想讓任何人知道
and he just didn't want anyone to know.
那為什么是你來告訴我
Then why are you telling me?
因為我幫著她一起為路易掩飾了
Because I helped her cover for him.
你是想說我該把你也炒了嗎
Are you saying I should fire you too?
我是想說
I am saying that...
我們是做錯了
we made a mistake,
但我們也是為了路易
but that we were just looking out for Louis,
而我知道你有多看重忠誠
and I know how much you value loyalty,
所以我覺得卡特里娜
so I don't think that should be the thing
不該為此丟了工作
that costs Katrina her job...
我也是
or mine.
-杰西卡  -我需要你
- Jessica. - I need you.
不  聽著  我需要一點時間
No, listen, I just need a little more time.
那你只要跟我開口  我會同意的
And had you asked me for it, I would have said yes,
可相反  你卻讓卡特里娜為你掩飾
but instead, you had Katrina cover for you.
那個小叛徒  她把我供出來了嗎
Oh, that little traitor. What, did she rat me out?
沒有  她對你很忠誠
No, she didn't. She's so loyal to you
甚至想頂替你做了你的工作
that she tried to pass off her work for yours.
路易  范·戴克想看我們的賬本
Louis, Van Dyke wants to look at our books.
什么  不能讓他這么做
What? We can't have that.
我知道  這是她的應對方案
I know. This was her fix.
哦不  你用了這個來對付他
Oh, no, and you used this on him?
對  所以我解雇了卡特里娜
I did, and then I fired Katrina.
-杰西卡  -我知道
- Jessica. - I know.
我不能因為她的忠誠而解雇她
I can't fire her for being loyal.
但現在已經火燒眉毛了  沒時間讓你
But I can't afford you sitting here licking your wounds
坐在這舔舐傷口
while I get my ass handed to me.
拜托  聽我說幾句  好嗎
Please, just listen to me, okay?
我現在無法明辨
I cannot see straight.
無法思考
I cannot think straight,
人人影視
YYeTs.com
即使我想幫你
and even if I wanted to come and help you,
我也毫無用處  所以...
I wouldn't be any good to you, so...
路易
Louis...
我知道你愛過希拉
I know you loved Sheila,
可你愛你的律所嗎
but do you love your firm?
你知道我愛的
You know I do.
當你愛上一個女人時
And when you love a woman,
想到她和別人在一起  你能忍受嗎
can you stand the thought of her being with another man?
-不  -那么  路易
- No. - Well, Louis,
范·戴克正在試圖扒了皮爾遜-斯佩克特的褲子
Van Dyke is trying to get into Pearson Specter's pants.
你要怎么做
What are you going to do about it?
我要牢牢系上貞操帶
I'm gonna put on a goddamn chastity belt.
怎么系
How?
卡特里娜的方向其實是對的
'Cause Katrina actually was on the right track.
只要取消合伙制度  他的要求就可以去見鬼了
Van Dyke's claim is gone if the partnership is gone.
公司章程可不是這么說的
The bylaws say it's not.
不  只要我們變成有限責任公司就行了
No, it is if we become an l.L.C.
但在明天之前是做不到的
We can't do that by tomorrow.
我們得重新起草每一份合同
We'd have to rewrite every contract.
杰西卡  你有時候真讓我服了
Boy, wow, Jessica, you sometimes really surprise me.
你以為我不知道這點嗎
You don't think I know that?
我的助理律師部隊
I have an army of associates that I've trained
曾被我精心調教得死去活來
within an inch of their lives.
我可是鬼見愁路易·馬洛·利特
My name is Louis goddamn Marlowe Litt,
現在我的律所被圍攻了  所以你別來告訴我
and my firm is under siege, so don't you tell me
什么能做什么不能做
what I can and cannot do!
我不想打擾你  就是有點好奇
I don't want to interrupt, but I was just wondering
邁克怎么了
what happened with Mike.
他要辭職
He's leaving.
真遺憾
I'm sorry.
沒事
It's fine.
能問你點事嗎
Can I ask you something?
你有沒有告訴他  你希望他留下
Did you tell him that you wanted him to stay?
我沒機會說
I didn't get around to it.
你沒機會說
You--you didn't get around to it?
我正打算說  他就告訴我他要走
I was gonna tell him, and then he told me he was leaving,
之后又發生了一堆破事  所以
and then other shit came up, so...
所以你就放棄了
So you just dropped it?
我說了  發生了別的破事
I told you other shit came up.
什么破事
What other shit?
難道你突然來了個案子
I mean, you had an emergency case filing,
所以就讓你徒弟這么走了
so you let your protege walk out the door?
-事情很復雜  -好吧
- It's complicated. - Okay.
那就跟我說說
Well, then share it with me.
柯靈纏上我們了  因為海辛頓案的目擊者
Quelling came after us. The Hessington witnesses.
什么  真是扯淡
What? That's bullshit.
或許你是鉆了點法律的空子
You may have blurred some lines,
但你絕對沒有越界違法
but you certainly didn't cross any.
反擊他
Fight him.
-我不能  -為什么
- No, I can't. - why?
我不想談這個
Look, I don't want to talk about it.
怎么回事  如果有人激怒你
What is going on here? When somebody pisses you off,
-你只會打得他屁滾尿流  -你想說什么
- you get in the ring. - What are you saying?
我想說你不僅沒有反擊柯靈
What I'm saying is that you're not taking on Quelling,
反而還讓邁克走了
but you're letting Mike walk out the door
甚至沒有試圖阻攔他
without trying to stop him.
肯定是有什么變了
I think one thing changed the other,
我想知道原因
and I want to know why.
或許是他變了  不愿留在這了
Maybe what changed is his desire to be here,
或許我要說的根本不重要
and maybe what I have to say doesn't matter.
那很重要  到底是什么事
Of course it matters. Now, what is this really about?
肯定跟什么破案子無關
Because it's sure as hell not about some stupid case.
去他媽的無關
You know what? God damn it!
我說是什么事就是什么事  不行嗎
For once, can't it just be about what I said it's about?
你根本沒說過是什么事
You didn't say what it was about.
哈維  我真的很遺憾
Harvey, I'm really sorry
邁克的事結果變成這樣
that the Mike thing turned out this way.
真的  但我得說我猜到了會這樣
I am, but I can't say that I didn't see it coming.
-斯科特  這不是  -什么  不是什么
- Scottie, it isn't-- - What? It isn't what?
不是表面上看起來那樣
It isn't what it seems?
我都不知道表面上看起來什么樣
Because I don't know what it seems.
我只知道每次我問你什么事
All I know is that any time I ask you about anything,
你都只會告訴我你不能說
all you say is, "I can't talk about it."
所以我不會再問了
I'm just gonna stop asking.
反正之后我們會和好
Then we'll just make up later,
然后明天同樣的事又會再次上演
and we can do it all over again tomorrow.
柯靈對我們沒威脅了
Quelling can't hurt us anymore.
-你去見羅拉了  -我查了他的賬戶
- You went to see Lola. - I looked at his accounts.
我想查出他哪來的錢
I wanted to find out where all that money came from
去找來這么多委托人
to find all those clients.
他沒錢
He doesn't have the money.
可他卻付清了房租
And yet his rent gets paid,
也沒被斷電
and they don't turn off his electricity.
我了個去
Holy shit.
看來你不用去見羅拉了
Guess you didn't have to see Lola after all.
你以為我是靠法院指令進他賬戶的嗎
You think I got access to that with a court order?
所以你還是去見羅拉了
So you did go see her?
是你的主意
You put the idea in my head.
我不過改了改具體內容
I just came up with a different agenda.
我們解決他了
We got him.
不
No.
-是你解決了  -什么
- You got him. - What?
算你的餞別禮
Your going-away present.
最后當一把律師  給他點教訓
Be a lawyer one last time. Knock this guy out.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
你帶支票來了嗎
You have my settlement check.
一分錢都沒有
I don't have a dime for you.
那我明天得一早就要去委員會
Then I guess the bar is going to be hearing from me
打個報告了
first thing in the morning.
那我也會去
Well, then, they'll also be hearing from me.
準則第5-107條A款  "接受..."
Disciplinary rule 5-107a, "Accepting compensation--"
我知道條款內容
I know what it says.
那你也知道懲罰是剝奪律師資格
Then you also know The penalty is being disbarred.
你收了我方客戶競爭對手的錢
You took money from our client's competitors
捏造了案子
to trump up your bullshit suit.
你這消息不是合法獲得的吧
You didn't come by that legally.
委員會才不關心呢
And they're not gonna care.
不知道你是否注意到
I don't know if you've noticed,
但我了無牽掛
but I don't have a hell of a lot to lose,
要么簽協議  要么就滾出去
so sign my deal or get the hell out of my office.
不過事實是  詹姆斯
Well, here's the thing, James.
我也是
I don't either...
因為今天是我最后一天做律師
Because today is my last day as a lawyer anyway.
-你就忽悠吧  -看著我
- Bullshit. - Look at me.
祝你去委員會好運
Good luck in front of the bar.
我并非一直如此
I wasn't always like this.
煙草公司一案勝利近在咫尺
I had tobacco in my sights.
他們愿意出很多錢
They offered me a lot of money.
我本可以大賺一筆
I could have made a fortune.
但就給患有癌癥的人一人一萬五
But $15,000 per client for people with cancer?
我冒險等判決  因為我想
I risked going to verdict because I wanted to
為那些人拿到更多錢  能讓生活有所不同
get those people something that could make a difference!
結果我失去了一切
And I lost everything...
客戶  妻子  孩子
My clients, my wife, my kids!
你失去他們是因為你的賭癮  詹姆斯
You lost them because you gambled them away, James.
我知道
I know that.
求你了
Please.
我生來就是律師
Being a lawyer is what I am.
是我的生命
It's who I am.
若你奪走...
And if you take that away...
決定權在你  詹姆斯
It's up to you, James.
我會撤銷訴訟
I'll drop the suit.
我保證
I promise.
路易  你在哪呢
Louis, where the hell are you?
你說你做得到
You said you could get it done.
我要是走進去  就都晚了
I walk through those doors, our books fly open.
趕緊過來
Get here now.
這回肯定很帶勁
Well, this should be fun.
我們還沒來沒做過對手
We've never been across the aisle from each other.
所以你才不知道我的厲害
Which is why you don't realize that it won't be fun.
我們走著瞧
We'll see what we see.
第41432號案件  范·戴克訴皮爾遜
Case 41432, Van Dyke versus Pearson.
瞧  游戲開始
Look at that. Game time.
-女士優先  -女士優先
- Ladies first. - Ladies first.
-狗娘養的  -禮貌也有錯
- Son of a bitch. - For being polite?
你當初雇傭我時  是出于禮節嗎
Were you being polite when you hired me?
這跟現在又有什么關系
What does one have to do with the other?
致錄取我的人  感謝你所做的一切
"To the man who hired me, for all you've done."
你想知道我寫那張卡是為了什么嗎
Do you want to know what I meant when I wrote that card?
你同意雇傭我時  我問過你
The day you made me that offer, I asked you,
這跟性別或種族有沒有關系
"Did it have anything to do with gender or race?"
你發誓說沒有
You swore it didn't.
你騙了我
You lied to me.
-是沒有  -你現在還在撒謊
- It didn't. - You're lying now.
丹尼爾·哈德曼雖會利用別人
You know, Daniel Hardman may have used people,
但他從不關心性別
but he didn't give a shit about their gender
或膚色
or their color.
他給你看了名單
He showed you the list.
在我名字旁有個星號  不是說我突出
Right next to my name, an asterisk. Not "Law review."
也不是標明我的成績  而是為了多樣化
Not second in my class. Diversity.
對你的待遇是一樣的
You were treated the same.
你可以這么告訴自己  但我們都知道真相
You tell yourself that, but we both know the truth,
這也是我能夠安心入睡的原因
which is why I sleep at night just fine.
但這并不會改變這個案子的實質對吧
Well, it doesn't change the facts in this case, does it?
不  不會  但這個會
No. No, it doesn't, but this will.
查爾斯  你記得路易·利特吧
Charles, you remember Louis Litt?
對不起  我不能跑過來
Sorry, I couldn't run.
醫生讓我不要太著急
Doctor wanted me to take it easy.
你好  查爾斯
Hey, Charles.
很高興見到你
Great to see you.
你講那個故事只是為了拖延時間吧
You told me that story to stall.
確實是為了拖時間
That was a stall...
但接下來是為了我自己
But this is for me.
當我看到我名字旁邊的注釋時
When I saw that asterisk next to my name,
真是讓我覺得惡心  因為我立刻就明白
it made me sick to my stomach, because in one second,
你會用一種什么樣的眼光看我了
I understood how you will always see me.
所以那張卡確實是代表感謝
So that card was a thank you,
因為如果我沒有感到惡心
because if I hadn't have felt sick,
我就不會如此努力的工作
then I might not have worked as hard as I did
從而取得現在的成就
to get where I am today.
你喚醒了沉睡的巨龍  查爾斯
You woke the dragon, Charles.
你現在覺得我怎么樣
How do you like me now?
人人影視
YYeTs.com
我知道你在那
I know you're there.
需要我做些什么嗎
You need anything?
不用
No.
公開募股的事情搞定了
The I.P.O. is wrapped up.
周一早晨上市
We go public monday morning.
我不是指公開募股的事
I wasn't talking about the I.P.O.
我是在說邁克的事
I was talking about how you're feeling about Mike.
我知道
I know.
好吧
Okay.
晚安  哈維
Good night, Harvey.
我準備告訴斯科特
I'm gonna tell Scottie.
邁克的事  你瘋了嗎
About Mike? Are you crazy?
你不能二者兼得  唐娜
You can't have it both ways, Donna.
你不能讓我敞開心扉的同時還要保守秘密
You can't tell me to open up and then keep my secrets.
你花了一年多的時間去掩蓋這件事
You spent more than a year covering it up.
你還試圖讓他再次犯罪去掩蓋原來的錯誤
You tried to get him to commit another crime to cover it up,
-現在呢  -你說我應該告訴她
- and now-- - You said I should tell her
到底是什么事情讓我煩惱
what's really bothering me!
我是說你的感受
I meant your feelings.
而不是承認一項罪行
I didn't mean confess to a felony.
這就是我的感受
These are my goddamn feelings!
唐娜  我雇他的時候做了些事情
Donna, I did something when I hired him.
導致了現在這些問題
It's caused all of this.
但我不能告訴她  這快把我逼瘋了
I can't tell her, and it's driving me crazy!
好吧  邁克就要走了  哈維
Okay. Look, Mike is gone, Harvey.
我雖然不愿意他走  但這樣威脅也沒了
I hate that he's gone, but the jeopardy's gone too.
都結束了
It's done.
現在你卻想回過頭告訴一個...
And now you want to turn around and tell someone who--
一個什么
Someone who what?
沒什么
Nothing.
不行  你最好把話說完
No, you better finish that sentence.
一個生你氣的人  哈維
Someone who's pissed at you, Harvey.
一個一直找理由生你氣的人
Someone who keeps finding a reason to be pissed at you,
不是第三次了  也不是第五次
and it's not the third time, and it's not the fifth time,
當然也不是最后一次
and it's not the last time.
我認為你是在試圖
I thought you were trying
幫我解決感情問題  而不是添亂
to help my relationship, not shit on it.
你可以對我喊  沒事
Okay, you want to yell at me? Fine.
因為我知道你不生我的氣
Because I know you're not mad at me.
我也知道你告訴這個愚蠢的主意
And I know you're only telling me this stupid idea
只是因為你想我告訴你一些你已經知道的事
because you want me to tell you what you already know.
你不能  哈維
You can't, Harvey.
你想告訴她這很好  但你不能說
It's good that you want to, but you can't.
能給我點時間嗎
Could I have a minute?
祝賀我吧
Congratulate me.
我真是成為紐約律師協會的一員了
I'm officially a member of the New York bar.
你去找羅拉了
You went to Lola?
我犯了個錯誤  我想留下來
I made a mistake. I want to stay.